## Pankaj Mishra (Doctoral Researcher)

University of Udine, Friuli-Venezia Giulia, Italy



pankajmishra000@gmail.com



(+39)-3201434039 / (+91)-7485890567



/pankaj-mishra-86898140



pankajmishra000



/pankajmishra000



pankajmishra000.github.io/000/

## **Summary**

Currently, Pankaj is doing his Ph.D. (externally sponsored by beanTech srl, an Italian technology company) at University of Udine in the field of Computer vision and Artificial Intelligence. His daily work includes developing models that can do real-life complex classification tasks, like anomaly detection, object detection, etc, in industrial application domain.

Research area - Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Anomaly Detection

Apart from this Pankaj also practices and teaches Yoga regularly and practices a healthy and active lifestyle.

## Experience

#### **AXISCADES**

Assistant Engineer Analyst - Jan 2015 - Sept 2016

#### Airbus India Operations

Material and Processes Engineer (Subcontracted by AXISCADES) Apr 2015 - Jul 2016

#### Safran Engineering Services

R&D Stress Analysis Engineer - Dec 2013 - Jul 2014

#### Technology Training and Research Centre

Trainee (CAE+CAD) - Aug 2013 - Nov 2013

#### Education



### Università degli Studi di Udine

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Artificial Intelligence and Computer Vision (2018 -2021)

**Supervisor:** *Prof. Gian Luca Foresti* 

The Ph.D. is intended to develop novel "Deep Neural Network" for complex classification tasks in real world industrial scenarios. Work majorly focuses on anomaly detection and computer vision. Thesis under writing...

Industrial Sponsored researcher (by beanTech srl)

# InterMaths : Erasmus Mundus Joint Master Degree & Double Degree Programmes

Master's in Interdisciplinary mathematics in Engineering and Finance. Spent two years in two different universities.

**Thesis:** "Some transformation of Multivariate Normal Random Vectors and Their Application to Statistics"

**Supervisor**: *Dr Agnieszka Kulawik* 

#### University of Silesia in Katowice (5/5)

Master's degree, Applied Mathematics in Finance (2017 - 2018)



Master's Degree, Mathematical Modelling in Engineering (2016 - 2017)

## Uttar Pradesh Technical University

B.Tech, Aeronautical Engineering (2009 - 2013)

Mark: 80.08%

### Army School Danapur Cantt, Patna, Bihar

AISSCE- {12TH} CBSE BOARD, Math's + Computers 2007 - 2009

Mark - 83.2%

### Army School Danapur Cantt, Patna, Bihar

AISSE {10TH} CBSE BOARD 2006 - 2007

Mark - 88.4%

## **Publications**

#### Journal

## A Neural Network for Image Anomaly Detection with Deep Pyramidal Representations and Dynamic Routing.

Mishra P, Piciarelli C, Foresti GL.

International Journal of Neural Systems. 2020 Oct;30(10):2050060. DOI: 10.1142/s0129065720500604.

## Supervised Anomaly Detection with Highly Imbalanced Datasets Using Capsule Networks

Piciarelli, Claudio, Pankaj Mishra, and Gian Luca Foresti. International Journal of Pattern Recognition and Artificial Intelligence (2021): 2152010.DOI: 10.1142/S0218001421520108

#### Conferences

## "VT-ADL: A Vision Transformer Network for Image Anomaly Detection and Localization"

P. Mishra, R. Verk, D. Fornasier, C. Piciarelli, G.L. Foresti 30th IEEE/IES International Symposium on Industrial Electronics (ISIE) Kyoto, Japan, June 20-23, 2021

## "Image Anomaly Detection by Aggregating Deep Pyramidal Representations" Mishra P., Piciarelli C., Foresti G.L.

In: Del Bimbo A. et al. (eds) Pattern Recognition. ICPR International Workshops and Challenges. ICPR 2021. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 12664. Springer, Cham. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-68799-1\_51, March 05, 2021

## Image Anomaly Detection with Capsule Networks and Imbalanced Datasets *Piciarelli C., Mishra P., Foresti G.L. (2019)*

In: Ricci E., Rota Bulò S., Snoek C., Lanz O., Messelodi S., Sebe N. (eds) Image Analysis and Processing – ICIAP 2019. ICIAP 2019. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11751. Springer, Cham. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-30642-7\_23, September 02,2019

### **Certification and Licenses**

Data Science: R Basics (HarvardX: PH125.1x) - edX

bb7ef02f64574bebac62c4b1602d691d

Data Science with Data Camp - DataCamp
#4,575,621

**DAT236x: Deep Learning Explained** - Microsoft

611e36b954b24453b773dedba1cda56d

**DEV210x: Introduction to C++** - Microsoft

847cc169f8394c17a0db8085a9ba42e0

## Skills

## **Machine Learning**

- Neural networks/Deep learning, metric learning, neural trees, support vector machines, incremental learning, dimensionality reduction, optimization, few shot learning, Classical ML
- Environments/Tools: pytorch, torch, tensorflow, keras, python, c/c++, anaconda, spyder, pycharm, SQL and Non-SQL databses

### **Computer Vision**

- visual understanding/recognition/detection/tracking, feature learning, feature extraction, feature Matching, anomaly detection, anomaly localization, camera setting, optical flow, classical CV
- Environments/Tools: pytorch, python, c#, c/c++, spyder, pycharm, matlab, visual studio

## Honors, Awards and Grants

**Ph.D. Grant by External Institution (beanTech srl), 2018** – Grant covers the Ph.D. scholarship and all research cost during the period of my PhD research.

**Hackathon Uniud Winner, 2019** - Won Hackathon organized by university of Udine in June 2019 by providing deep learning solution to an industrial problem within 24 hrs.

**Erasmus+ Grant** - Erasmus grant covers all the expenses of dual master's degree in Italy and Poland.

**Erasmus Social** - Erasmus Student Network, Nov 2017, awarded for participating in the Social Erasmus programs organized by Erasmus Student Network, Poland.

Achievement of Merit - Feroze Gandhi Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sep 2010, Awarded for the best performance in academics in year 2009-2010.

edX Grant - Received grant from edX which covered 95% of the certification cost for 1) Basic in R - by Harvard University 2) Deep learning Explained and C++ by Microsoft

## **Member and Association**

- IAPR Italian Association of Pattern Recognition, Italian Chapter 2018 till date
- · Reviewer for Elsevier Artificial Intelligence in Medicine
- · Reviewer for International Journal of Neural Systems

## Language

- English Professional Fluency (almost native)
- o Hindi /Bhojpuri native
- o Italian B1
- o Polish A1

## Teaching activities

 Cybersecurity and Unsupervised Machine Learning April - July 2020, 16 hrs academic course, University of Udine, Italy

## References

#### Prof. Gian Luca Foresti (Ph.D. supervisor)

Email: gianluca.foresti@uniud.it

Phone: +39 0432 558402

#### Prof. Claudio Piciarelli (Ph.D. co-supervisor)

Email: claudio.piciarelli@uniud.it

Phone: +39 0432 558481